

Kate Hinrichs

Software Developer

ko.hinrichs@gmail.com | 763.772.4512



/kohinrichs



/in/kate-hinrichs



kohinrichs.github.io

After frustrating experiences implementing new software for wholesale clients and staff at a bakery and then trying to create a pandemic pre-ordering system within the structure of existing software, I applied for the software development program at Nashville Software School. As someone who is motivated to find efficient and effective solutions, I wanted to learn how to build software so I could help businesses - both big and small - create the tools they need to address their unique challenges.

Technical Skills

- Git & Github version control
- Remote project collaboration using Zoom and Slack
- Creating ERDs, dependency charts, and wireframe designs
- Developing applications using JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS., and C#/.Net

Projects

Personal - MOBI MOVES

Github: /kohinrichs/mobi-moves

Used **React**, **JavaScript**, **HTML**, and **CSS** to build an app that lets users create their own interval training workouts with moves they already know. Users add moves to their exercise library and use those moves to build workouts. Favorite workouts can be saved and used again and again.

Group - Holiday Road

Used **JavaScript**, **HTML**, and **CSS** to team build an app that allows users to create and save trip agendas utilizing external **APIs**

Education

Iowa State University | Graduated May 2011 Cum Laude | Bachelor of Science Apparel Merchandising & Design Concentration - Product Development

Technical Experience

Nashville Software School | Graduating Spring 2021 A six month, full-time, intensive program with a focus on project based teaching methods and emphasis on learning to think like a software developer.

Experience

Dozen Bakery | **37203** | **Operations + Facilities Manager** | April 2018 - June 2020

- Researched sourcing options for ingredients and paper goods and implemented changes in sourcing that lead to a 7% decrease in overall COGS in a year with a 10% increase in gross revenue
- Created and maintained an ingredient and paper goods price tracking system
- Designed systems for ingredient and supply ordering, developed and launched new wholesale customer management system, organized 500+ Thanksgiving orders
- Wrote training documents for new systems and several roles at the bakery and trained employees using the documents
- Guided daily operations, answered customer emails, organized special orders
- Did whatever needed to be done to make sure everyone else could be successful at their jobs
- Technologies: Squarespace, Square, Wix, My Online Bakery, Quickbooks Online, Google Sheets

Project Manager | September 2017 - April 2018

- Created content and managed social media accounts (Instagram, Facebook, Twitter)
- Organically grew Instagram following by 6,000+ followers over 3 years

Baker (Pastry Team) | March 2017 - August 2017

 Production baker with focus on the 3am early bake and large batches of cookie and pie dough in the 60qt mixer

Nestle Toll House | 60607 | Lead Baker | October 2016 - January 2017

- Led a team with a variety of personality types
- Acted as a brand ambassador for an internationally recognized company and brand during Act of Good deliveries and radio and TV interviews
- Thoughtfully approached delicate and emotional situations; tactfully addressed negative comments
- Documented the process and event execution with photographs, videos, and written blog posts for Nestle Toll House social media channels
- Researched potential Acts of Good, pitched events to causes/organizations, acted as a liaison between bakers, management staff, and organizations
- Developed and/or selected recipes appropriate for Act of Good organizations

•

Flavor Catering & Special Occasions | 37203 | Hospitality Liaison + Kitchen Lead | May 2015 - May 2019

- Balanced the expectations of the client with the reality of the situation while offering the highest-quality experience and service
- Executed buffets and plated meals for 20 300 people and managed a team of 3 8 kitchen staff with consideration of the event timeline
- Prepared detailed appetizers, salads, and desserts at event site
 Navigated unexpected situations and worked in challenging conditions (outdoors, in garages and barns, sites with no running water)
- Ensured the proper food and equipment left the kitchen and arrived at the event
- Analyzed musician rider requirements, shopped for requests, set dressing rooms, and worked with tour management to ensure all hospitality needs were met while keeping in mind budget and time constraints

The Peach Truck | 37208 | Farm to Porch Director | May 2016 - August 2016

- Lead the FTP team through a season of unprecedented growth (the team shipped more boxes of peaches in the first week of the season than they had in the ENTIRE previous season.)
- Facilitated the shipment of more FTP orders than in any previous season
- Developed processes and trained the Farm to Porch team as to best practices for sorting peaches, packing boxes, and adhering shipping labels
- Printed and organized labels for all orders
- Personally handwrote custom notes or delegated the task when appropriate
- Worked closely with the customer service team to address order issues and provide top-notch customer service
- Communicated inventory restrictions and/or needs to management and customer service teams

• Technologies : Shipstation, Slack	
-------------------------------------	--

Nisolo | 37208 | Project Manager / Community Outreach Coordinator | July 2012 - June 2014

- Processed shipments of shoes from Peru (cleaning, sorting, boxing, documenting, and counting) and later led groups of interns in the process
- Generated content and managed social media platforms (Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram)
- Set up/built product displays, planned pop-up events, and contributed to \$100,000+ in event sales over a two year time period
- Crafted customer experience through in-person service at the Nashville showroom and via social media platforms, phone calls, and emails
- Researched and executed major projects such as workspace redesign
- Managed and organized intern and employee job applications
- Point of contact for local and national publications, bloggers, students, and general inquiries
- Technologies : Square, Shopify, Shipstation, Quickbooks Online, Asana